

Creative professional with 11+ years of experience in all stages of the web discovery, design, and development process within a wide variety of industries.

Possesses a strong design background while being well-versed in several programing languages and open-source platforms.

Collaborates well with teams to establish strategic and engaging solutions.

Contact Information

- Baltimore, Maryland
- in matthewjcurtin
- mcurtin.github.io
- @matthewjcurtin
- 410.206.4492
- mjcurtin1@gmail.com

Skills & Certifications

- CMS Platforms (Drupal, Magento, WordPress)
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Design Systems (Style Guides, PatternLab)
- Prototyping with InVision, Sketch, Adobe XD
- User Interface Design & Wireframes
- User Persona & Story Development
- Bootstrap (3/4) & Foundation (5/6) Frameworks
- Agile Design & Development Workflow
- HTML5, TWIG, PHP, XML, CSS3, LESS, SASS
- Magento Certified Front End Developer
- Acquia Certified Site Builder
- Agency Team Workload & Time Management

Please contact for portfolio of recent work.

Experience

Creative Director

Unleashed Technologies | Columbia, Maryland August 2011 - Present

Creative Director (April 2018 - Present)

- Develop design strategies for clients by evaluating objectives, KPIs and KSAs.
- Review and approve user experience and user interface plans and content developed by design team
- Plan, schedule, and complete design and production for all client and internal initiatives.
- Improve quality of deliverables by evaluating and enhancing agency creative processes.

Sr. Frontend Developer (October 2015 - April 2018)

- Lead designer and frontend developer on several open-source platforms, including Magento & Drupal.
- Developed both wireframes and design concepts for both CMS & e-commerce projects.
- Implement approved concepts leveraging the latest HTML5 & CSS3 best practices.
- Mentor & guide several team members both in design & development.

Web Designer (August 2011 - October 2015)

- Work closely with developers to achieve a well-deigned user interface on the Magento and Drupal platforms.
- Lead designer for several web initiatives & builds.

Web Designer

Galley Creative Group | Ellicott City, Maryland July 2009 - August 2011

- Primary web designer & developer leveraging several content management systems, including Joomla, Drupal, WordPress and Magento.
- Design websites so that they are visually effective, and on brand.

Education

BA in Visual Arts, BA in Media Communications University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC) GPA: 3.6.3/4.0 Cum Laude, Graduation: May 2009

Member of the UMBC Men's Lacrosse Team, Golden Key Honor Society, Dean's List (Spring 2006, 2007, 2008)